A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Oscar Harkavy FA623
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Chronological Correspondence, Information Papers, Conference, 1977-1981
  - Bellagio Conference on Health and Population in Developing Countries -- Background Papers, Apr 18-21, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Bellagio IV Population Conference -- Working Papers, Nov 1977 (Box 15)
- Conferences, 1965-1980
  - World Population Conference -- Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Elsinore (1/2), June 1972 (Box 16)
  - Elsinore (2/2), Jun 1972 (Box 16)
  - ASEAN Population Meetings -- Bali, Jun 23-28, 1977 (Box 16)
  - News Briefing for Science Writers -- New Developments in Contraception and Fertility Control, Dec 14, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Folder #1 -- Meeting on Social Science Research and Population -- Lists -- People, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Folder #1 -- Meeting on Social Science Research and Population -- Strategy Paper, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Folder #1 -- Meeting on Social Science Research and Population -- Working Papers, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Interagency Collaboration on Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Proceedings, Feb 24-25, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- Agenda Master Copy, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- I-A, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- II, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- III, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- IV, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- V, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- VI, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Master Session Materials -- Ford Foundation Memoranda, 1974 (Box 16)
  - PLAMIRH Meeting, Bogota, Apr 1974 (Box 16)
  - Minutes of Meeting, International Committee for Contraception Research, Mar 13-15, 1974 (Box 16)
  - PIACT -- Coordinating Committee Meeting, Apr 23-29, 1979 (Box 16)
  - PIACT, Sep 15-Nov 17, 1977 (Box 16)
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons of Columbia University -- Center for Population and Family Health, 1978 (Box 16)
  - Reproductive Biology Strategy File, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Meeting at Rockefeller Foundation Targeted Program, Sep 30, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development -- Miscellaneous Publications and Correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box 16)
- Log Notes, Conferences, 1964-1974
  - Communications Aspects of Family Planning programs, Dec 2-12, 1968 (Box 17)
  - India -- Log Notes/Papers, 1963-1969 (Box 17)
  - Indonesia -- Log Notes/Reports, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Malaysia -- Log Notes/Program Papers, 1964-1970 (Box 17)
  - Malaysia -- Background Papers, 1964 (Box 17)
  - Pakistan, Apr 1970 (Box 17)
  - Philippines -- Log Notes, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Singapore/Japan -- Log Notes/Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - Thailand, 1970 (Box 17)
  - United Nations -- Conference on Demography -- Lyon, France, Jun 3-11, 1971 (Box 17)
  - United Nations Expert Working Group on Population Research in National Institutions, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Bellagio Meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 17)
  - All India Women's Conference, 1973 (Box 17)
  - International Economic Association -- Conference on Economic Aspects of Population Growth, Sep 1973 (Box 17)
  - Population Association of America, Apr 18-20, 1974 (Box 17)
- Conferences, General Files, 1967-1977
  - London Conference on Public Sector Involvement in Reproductive Science and Contraceptive Research (1/2), Apr 1977 (Box 18)
  - London Conference on Public Sector Involvement in Reproductive Science and Contraceptive Research (2/2), 1977 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1/2), 1968-1977 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2/2), 1968-1977 (Box 18)
  - Marrimon Cuninggim, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 18)
  - The Population Chronicle, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Papal Encyclical, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Box 18)
  - Resource Base Meetings (1/2), 1967-1970 (Box 18)
  - Resource Base Meetings (2/2), 1967-1970 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
- Meetings, Visits, Budget, 1963-1975
  - Budgets, 1963-1968 (Box 19)
  - Africa Consultancy Visit, Jan 16-Mar 2, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Africa Trip Report -- Attachments A-M, May 15-30, 1973 (Box 19)
  - West Africa, May 1973 (Box 19)
  - International Division -- Population Office -- Budget Planning, 1973-1975 (Box 19)
  - Budget FY1972 (1/2), 1971 (Box 19)
  - Budget FY1972 (2/2), 1971 (Box 19)
  - Budget Papers -- Miscellaneous FY1971, 1970 (Box 19)
  - International Division -- Budget FY1970, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Budget Meeting -- Planning, Exploration and Evaluation, Apr 1972 (Box 19)
- Budgets, Meetings, 1969-1975
  - Reproductive Biology, 1973-1975 (Box 20)
  - Budget Memoranda, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Budget FY1980, May 1974 (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation Population Meeting -- Cali, Colombia (1/2), Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation Population Meeting -- Cali, Colombia (2/2), Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - Social Science Research Meeting at the Ford Foundation, Oct 29-30, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Conference on Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Background Papers, Oct 29-30, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Conference on Social Science Research on Population and Development -- Miscellaneous, 1974-1975 (Box 20)
  - Meeting on Assistance to Education, Sep 16-18, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Third Meeting on Education and Development -- Bellagio Italy -- Working Papers, Jul 7-10, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Language and Development -- A Retrospective Survey, 1975 (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation Interim Report on Surveys of Social and Management Sciences Relevant to Population Problems, Jun 10, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Proposed Budget FY1970 -- Papers, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Proposed Budget FY1971, Jun 1970 (Box 20)
  - Proposed Budget FY1972, Jun 1971 (Box 20)
- Correspondence Subject Files, Conference, 1970-1976
  - Correspondence -- To Sign, 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, 1975-1978 (Box 21)
  - United Nations -- Social Science Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - West Africa, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Population Council -- Miscellaneous Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 21)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East -- Asian Population Conference, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Population Related Social Science Research in the Middle East and Africa -- Background Materials, Sep 30-Oct 1, 1971 (Box 21)
- Subject Files, 1967-1970
  - Senate Labor and Public Welfare Committee Hearings, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Implementing DHEW Policy on Family Planning and Population, 1967 (Box 22)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - United Nations Association -- World Population Report [PHOTO], 1969 (Box 22)
  - House Ways and Means Material (1/2), 1969 (Box 22)
  - House Ways and Means Material (2/2), 1969 (Box 22)
- Correspondence and Subject Files, Meetings, Budget, 1968-1974
  - World Health Organization (WHO) -- Karoliwsky, 1971 (Box 23)
  - ACORD -- Egon Diczfalusy, Apr 1970 (Box 23)
  - WHO (Informal File), Jun 1970 (Box 23)
  - Reproductive Biology, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Djerassi, Carl -- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Contraceptive Development, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Consortium Meeting, Nov 1969 (Box 23)
  - Reproductive Biology Consortium, 1968-1969 (Box 23)
  - Karolinska, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Meeting, May 13, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Bellagio, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Serbelloni Population Meeting, Apr 6-8, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Working Papers for Villa D'Este Meeting, Apr 1968 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Population Consultants Conference, Lake Como, Italy, Apr 1968 (Box 23)
  - Social and Management Sciences -- Asia -- Background Materials A-G, Oct 1, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Ford Foundation Interim Report on Surveys of Social and Management Sciences Relevant to Population Problems, Jun 10, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Background Papers, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Population Office -- Draft Budget -- FY1974-1975 (Box 23)
- Subject Files, 1968-1981
  - Perkin, Gordon W., Feb 1968-Nov 1980 (Box 24)
  - Kavoori, J.C. -- Executive Director, Family Planning Foundation (India), 1977-1980 (Box 24)
  - Khew, Dr. K.S. -- Operative Culdoscopy, Apr 1971-Feb 1972 (Box 24)
  - Kocher, James E. -- Family Planning in India, 1977-1981 (Box 24)
  - Korten, David C., 1978-1980 (Box 24)
  - Cycle Communications (W.O. Sweeney and Ann Leonard), 1980 (Box 24)
  - PIACT Grants, 1978-1980 (Box 24)
  - PLAMIRH, 1974-1981 (Box 24)
  - Sweeney, William O., 1973-1980 (Box 24)
  - Mahoney, Richard T. -- PIACT, 1979-1980 (Box 24)
  - Mahoney, Richard T. -- India, 1977-1978 (Box 24)
  - Mahoney, Richard T. -- Egypt, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Mahoney, Richard T. -- PIACT, 1975-1978 (Box 24)
  - Kantner, John F. -- Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 24)
- Subject Files
  - Population Resource Center (Corporate Program), 1980-1981 (Box 25)
  - Congressman Jas. Scheuer -- House Select Committee on Population -- Testimony, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Congressman Jas. Scheuer -- House Select Committee on Population -- House Select Committee Testimony, Mar 9, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Congressman Jas. Scheuer -- House Select Committee on Population -- Report on Population and Development, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Mr. Harvavy's DHEW Consultant Report and Correspondence on Related Topics, 1967-1968 (Box 25)
  - Panel of Consultants in Population, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Institute on Medical Education and Family Planning -- Association of American Medical Colleges, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - Population and Health -- Alma Ata (USSR) Conference on Primary Health Care, 1978 (Box 25)
  - Center for Public Resources, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Agency for International Development (AID), 1974-1979 (Box 25)
- David Bell Correspondence, Miscellaneous Papers, 1964-1982
  - Old Historical Documents, 1982 (Box 26)
  - David E. Bell Correspondence, Sep 1968-Jul 1970 (Box 26)
  - David E. Bell Correspondence, Aug 1970-Oct 1972 (Box 26)
  - David E. Bell Correspondence, May 1973-Dec 1977 (Box 26)
  - David E. Bell Correspondence, Jan 1978-Jan 1981 (Box 26)
  - Alza -- Planned Parenthood -- Ford Foundation -- Agreement -- Meeting Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Bangkok Meeting -- Relative Correspondence and Reports, May 2-5, 1978 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled) (1/5), 1964-1975 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled) (2/5), 1964-1975 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled) (3/5), 1964-1975 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled) (4/5), 1964-1975 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled) (5/5), 1964-1975 (Box 26)
- Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled), 1969-1970; Legal size document box
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Papers (unfiled material requiring no response from Oscar Harkavy), 1969-1970 (Box 27)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1970-1980
  - Harkavy, Oscar; Family Planning -- World Programs, May 1970 (Report #019931)
  - Harkavy, Oscar; Major Population Problems of the Next Decade -- the View from One Foundation, Apr 1980 (Report #019929)
  - Harkavy, Oscar; Testimony before the Task Force On Population Growth and Ecology, Apr 25, 1972 (Report #019930)